<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<brxml xmlns="http://www.dpawson.co.uk/ns#" xml:lang="en-UK" grade="1">
   <meta>
      <page>
         <width>40</width>
         <height>28</height>
         <header>Fixed header text <pagenum prefix="Page" align="end"/>
         </header>
      </page>
   </meta>
   <body>
      <para s="0" r="3">Paragraph First line start at column 0, remainder of lines are indented 3 cells.</para>

      <para>Para with default indent of 0,0. I.e. no indentation</para>

      <break type="page"/>
      <para align="center">Centred header etc.</para>
      <para>hdhdh </para>

      <para xml:space="preserve">
// Whitespace preservation example
 for (int i=0; i &lt; iMax; i++) {
    System.out.println("System Initialised");
 }
      </para>

<lit>Literal layout
already formatted and translated</lit>

    <para s="3" r="0">Text examples for layout.</para>
<para>Creating digital audio files for delivery to Peterborough on removable disks.</para>
<para>Overview. A process to deliver digital audio files to RNIB Peterborough.</para>
<para>Digital audio is generated by various UK locations which send it to RNIB for archiving. The removable disks are then returned by Peterborough for re-use.</para>
<para>In order to identify the document, it must be given a recognised production identification number (PIN). For processes internal to Peterborough, the Sage CBS system is used to produce this number. Talking books (Camden) have their own system (RMS). Until further notice, an identification number from the blocks below should be used by the providers listed. On request, any other RNIB provider will be issued with a block of such identification numbers, which should be used to identify digital audio sent to RNIB Peterborough.</para>
<para>Start End Allocated to</para>
<para>400000 402500 Dig Cass lib project</para>
<para>402501 403500 Peterborough Recording Studios</para>
<para>403501 404500 Ivybridge</para>
<para>404501 405500 Tarpoley</para>
<para>405501 406500 Leeds</para>
<para>406501 407500 RNIB Scotland</para>
<para>407501 408500 RNIB Cymru</para>
<para>408501 409500 RNIB Northern Ireland</para>
<para>409501 410500 Transcription, via John Durrant</para>
<para>410501 411500 Donations' via Mandy Thompson</para>
<para>411501 412500 Peterborough, Re-archiving</para>
<para>A document pro-forma should be filled in, commonly known as a 'NITS' form, Notification of Intention to Transcribe, and emailed to 'librarysystems@rnib.org.uk', which is used to enter initial information onto the RNIB catalogue system.</para>
<para>This pro-forma may be obtained from the same email address. A completed example is attached to this document in Microsoft Word format, see the file 'nitExample.doc'.</para>
<para>This production identification number should be used as the identifier for that document when the audio is sent to Peterborough, and included in the NITS submission.</para>
<para>For the rest of this document an example production identification number of 400101 will be used.</para>
<para>A folder is created for each new book or set of digital audio files on the root of the disk drive. Name the folder using the production identification number.</para>
<para>1. Daisy Digital Audio for going onto a single CD</para>
<para>The directory listing of the removable drive could look something like</para>
<para>The DAISY directory holds the daisy book as deliverable to the customer. The 'PROJECT' directory holds the project build files from the application used to create the Daisy book.</para>
<para>2. Daisy Digital Audio going onto more than one CD</para>
<para>If a daisy book carries on over more than one CD, use names ending in the disk number, e.g. PART1 PROJECT1 PART2 PROJECT2 etc.</para>
<para>E.g. for a 2 book Daisy book it appears as follows;</para>
<para>3. Non-Daisy digital audio going onto a single CD.</para>
<para>For digital audio files other than Daisy books, e.g. digital audio destined for a CD or cassette, the following structure should be used on the removable hard drive.</para>
<para>On the top of the directory create an appropriately named directory as above. In this directory there should be a single file named readme.txt which describes the digital audio for this item (See below for an example). In this directory put the files making up the digital audio. These files should be named 01.wav 02.wav etc.</para>
<para>Example layout</para>
<para>3. Non-Daisy digital audio going onto more than one CD.</para>
<para>If the audio will not fit onto one disk, the following disk layout should be used. This organisation splits the audio files into CD sized pieces and labels each directory as DISK1 DISK2 DISK3 etc. A readme.txt file remains in the root directory and the description field may be used to describe the way the book is split up.</para>
<para>The readme.txt file in the first disk directory describes the files used to create that CD. The label.txt file is used to create the printed label when the disk is re-generated for the customer. A label file is required for each CD which will be re-generated for the customer.</para>
<para>Example of files going onto 2 or more CD's.</para>
<para>An example contents of the DISK1 directory</para>
<para>The readme.txt The readme.txt file should be a plain text file laid out with at least the following information. It may be created with a word processor such as Microsoft Word, or using the Microsoft 'notepad' program.</para>
<para>Title: Document title.</para>
<para>Date: Date processed by the transcription centre in the format YYYY-MM-DD (Year, month and day of month). Transcription Centre: Name of the transcription centre. Reference: A reference identity, if available. Otherwise leave blank. Description: A textual description or additional information felt necessary to describe the audio files.</para>
<para>For example:</para>
<para>Title: Wind in the Willows</para>
<para>Date: 2006-01-26</para>
<para>Authority: Tarporley</para>
<para>Reference: ISBN-13: 978-0-19-283515-4</para>
<para>Description: Single CD. Synthetic voice.</para>
<para>The label file (label.txt) should contain the text required on the CD label. This should be restricted to 3 lines on one side of the centre of the CD, and two lines on the the other. Each line of text should be no more than 20 characters long, to enable clear print guidelines to be followed. This is how the text will be used.</para>
<para>A suitable file for a label.txt file might be</para>
<para>Mr Speaker</para>
<para>by George Thomas</para>
<para>05682</para>
<para>Daisy Master</para>
<para>Note that the last line is unused.</para>
<para>At an appropriate time, the disk is sent to Peterborough. The removable drive should be marked with the identity of the transcription centre and sent to:</para>
<para>RNIB,</para>
<para>Re-archiving Department,</para>
<para>Bakewell Road,</para>
<para>Peterborough PE2 6XU</para>
<para>In case of a query, Telephone 01733 375000and ask for the re-archiving department</para>
<para>Revision 1.1</para>
<para>Date 2006-02-07</para>
<para>Document identity. rnib.aio.daf.wi001.</para>
</body>
</brxml>